What does a civil rights icon like Martin Luther King Jr.,
a tech visionary like Steve Jobs, and a media mogul
like Oprah Winfrey have in common?
They all operate from a clear and powerful purpose.
Your purpose is your why.
It's your fundamental reason for being.
Separate from your job title,
it's the lasting impact you want to have.
And it's what drives you to take action
when the work gets hard.
And yet, according to Harvard Business Review,
fewer than 20% of leaders
have a strong written purpose statement,
and even fewer have written it down.
But today, you join the elite 10%.
But before we draft your own,
it's critical to understand what purpose truly is.
Think of your purpose as your personal operating system.
It's the underlying code that runs everything else,
your decisions, your actions, and your priorities.
When the operating system is installed and running,
you get powerful upgrades.
The first is the greater meaning in your life and work.
As an added bonus, research has shown
that living your purpose can increase resiliency,
improve sleep, and even decrease the risk
of cardiac disease.
But maybe the most powerful upgrade
is how this OS manages your most valuable resource, time.
Your purpose acts as a compass,
guiding your time management towards a life
that is not only efficient, but also fulfilling.
It's the difference between doing things correctly,
which is time management, and doing the right things,
which is purpose-driven leadership.
For me, my purpose is to awaken people
to the power of purpose as a catalyst
for remarkable leadership and a fulfilled life.
When this why hit me, I had lost everything
and struggled to keep this business alive.
I would tell myself, this why is bigger than you, Melissa.
Purpose can drive performance.
You will go global, Melissa.
And now, in over 26 countries and counting,
those words on my vision board were not fluff,
they were fuel, high octane, that is,
that eventually connected you and I in this very moment.
Notice, I didn't say I'm a CEO or I'm a coach.
It's the why behind everything that I do.
Knowing this why allows me to play to my strengths
and clarify boundaries, ensuring I'm operating
at my highest contribution.
A financial leader I know describes her purpose
as keeping my people from making short-sighted decisions
against their own self-interest.
It's about protection and wisdom.
A brilliant engineer I coached said his purpose
was to build elegant solutions
that makes complex things simple for people.
It's about creating clarity in a world of noise.
In a world of constant change and distraction,
your purpose is your anchor.
It gives you stability.
Having a clear purpose statement creates focus.
It clarifies your choices and defines your priorities
and defines how you operate each and every day.
When you're faced with two good opportunities,
your purpose statement is the tiebreaker.
It tells you which path is truly yours.
Now in your playbook, you'll find a drill
designed to help you draft your purpose statement.
Use the notes from lessons two,
your values, the moments that moved you.
This isn't about finding the perfect right words.
It's about getting the first draft down.
It's gotta feel authentic.
It will take time and it's okay
to have multiple drafts in this process.
Choose progress over perfection.